If we create a string variable called newsOutlet for example,
举个例子 如果我们创建一个叫 newsOutlet (新闻媒体) 的字符串变量
we can only store one value in it at a time.
那我们一次只能往里存放一个值
Arrays however allow us to store many strings in that same variable.
同样一个变量 如果是数组 则允许我们存放多个字符串
Each can have its own value.
而且每个字符串可以有自己的值
They all however have to be of the same type.
不过所有字符串的类型得一致
In this case, because this is an array of strings each value has to be a string.
在这个案例中 由于这是个字符串数组 所以每个值都得是字符串
And, since they're all stored in the same variable,
而且由于他们存放在同一个变量中
to tell them apart each part of the array is numbered always
为了分辨这些值 数组的每个部分都会标号
starting from zero and counting up for as many items exist in the array.
通常数组中含有多少项 就从 0 往上标到多少
If you want to retrieve the value inside any of those boxes,
如果你想取出存放在某个盒子里的值
you just have to type the arrays name followed by the square brackets,
你只需输入数组名 然后方括号
with the box number inside those squared brackets.
并在方括号里输入对应盒子的编号即可
For example, newsOutlet of zero has ABC in it.
例如 newsOutlet [0] 里放着 ABC
NewsOutlet of one has BBC in it
newsOutlet [1] 里有 BBC
and newsOutlet of two has CNN in it and so on for the rest of the array.
newsOutlet [2] 里有 CNN 以此类推
Each of those expressions can be treated as if they are normal variables. Let's see how.
所有这些表达式都能当普通变量使用 我们来看具体操作
In Java, you could think of any array as if it's one row of a table,
在 Java 里 对于任何数组 你都可以将其想成是一张表中的一行
where each box in the array has a different value but they all have the same name.
虽然数组里的每个盒子装着不同的值 但它们有共同的名字
In this example, I'm creating an array of
比如 我现在创建了一个整数数组
integers so each box would have an integer inside it.
所以每个盒子里会放着一个整数
Those boxes in Java are called cells.
在 Java 里 这些盒子叫做元素
As we've mentioned earlier,
正如我们之前说的
each of those cells is numbered starting from zero and counting up.
每个元素都有自己的编号 从 0 往上标起
These numbers are called the cell indices,
这些编号叫做元素索引
because each number is an index to a particular cell.
这是因为每个数字都是某个特定元素的索引
For example, this cell here has an index of zero.
比如 这个元素的索引号为 0
This cell here is the cell with index three.
这个元素的索引号为 3
We can treat each cell as if it was a separate variable.
我们可以把每个元素当作独立的变量来处理
Like for example if we wanted to add this cell here to that cell there,
比如 如果我们想将这个元素和这个加起来
we would just say something like this.
我们只需要这么写
Integer sum equals numbers of zero plus numbers of three.
int sum = numbers [0] +numbers [3]
Our array name is called numbers and we
我们的数组名叫做 numbers
just access the different cells using the indices like that.
而刚才我们做的 就是用不同索引访问了不同的元素
And then this statement here is just considered as if it was a variable.
这个语句是将它们当变量来处理的
We could add them together,
我们可以把两者相加
we could do anything we can with a normal variable.
我们可以对普通变量做什么 就可以怎么对它们
This would update our valuable sum to become 15.
这会把变量 sum 更新为 15
Because it's adding 12,
因为它是把 12
which has numbers of zero, two,
也就是 numbers [0]
three which is numbers of three giving us 15.
和 3 也就是 numbers [3] 相加 于是等于 15
But, how do we even declare those arrays in the first place?
可是 我们一开始要怎么声明这些数组呢？
Let's say we want to declare an array that looks something like this.
假设我们想要声明一个像这样的数组
We type in integer and then empty square brackets just to say that we want to
我们输入 int 然后是空的方括号 括号表示
create an array of integers not just a single
我们想创建的是一个整数数组 而不仅仅是一个整数
integer and then we write the name of our array.
然后写上数组的名字
Which in our case is called numbers and then we
在这里就叫 numbers
follow that by equals and then curly brackets.
然后就是等号和花括号
Inside those curly brackets,
在花括号里
we just list all the values we want to have in our array.
我们需要列举出所有想放在数组里的值
Notice that I didn't have to specify how big the array is.
注意 我不需要说明数组有多大
What Java would do, is it will just assign each of those values into
Java 会分别把这些值分配到其内存中的各元素里
a cell in its internal memory and it would assign each cell an index,
并给每个元素分配一个索引
so that if you want to reach the value 121,
所以如果你想找到值 121
you just have to access it using the index seven.
你只需用索引 7 来访问它
For example, if I tried to print out numbers of zero,
比如 如果我试着输出 numbers [0]
I get the output 12 because this is the value inside the cell with index zero.
那就会输出 12 因为索引为 0 的元素里就放着这个值
If I wanted to print out the result of
如果我想
the multiplication between numbers of 9 and numbers of 12,
输出 numbers [9] 和 numbers [12] 的乘积
that's basically negative 4 times 2,
也就是 - 4 乘以 2
then our output would be negative 8.
所以输出会是 - 8
An array of doubles is no different.
双精度数组也一样
For example if we wanted to create an array of doubles that looks something like this,
比如 如果我们想创建一组像这样的双精度数组
we just go ahead and say,
我们可以直接写
double and then empty square brackets again to separate it from a normal double.
double 然后还是方括号 以便把它和普通双精度数区分开来
And then we just put in the array name,
然后输入数组名字
followed by equals, curly brackets and we list the values inside.
后面是等号 花括号 并在括号中列举值